<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Food Security Portal News &amp; Blogs</title><link>https://www.foodsecurityportal.org/news-and-blogs</link><description>Latest updates from the Food Security Portal</description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 01:09:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>PyRSS2Gen-1.1.0</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Food Prices Fall in December But Remain Higher Overall in 2025: FAO Food Price Index</title><link>https://www.foodsecurityportal.org/node/3769</link><description>The FAO Food Price Index declined marginally in December, with prices reaching 2.3 percent below December 2024. Overall prices for 2025 remained 4.3 percent higher than 2024, however.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The future of food demand: Evidence from a global meta-analysis and trend projections</title><link>https://www.foodsecurityportal.org/node/3771</link><description>Understanding how food demand responds to income and price changes is essential for anticipating global food needs and expected consumption patterns, and for designing effective food policies. Two key parameters for this are the income elasticity of demand—the percent change in consumption in response to a percent change in people’s income; and the price elasticity of demand—the percent change in consumption in response to a percent food price change. These are essential inputs in a wide range of economic models.</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fertilizer prices soften but remain constrained by trade policies</title><link>https://www.foodsecurityportal.org/node/3765</link><description>This blog post is part of a special series based on the October 2025 Commodity Markets Outlook, a flagship report published by the World Bank. This series features concise summaries of commodity-specific sections extracted from the report. Explore the full report here.</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>While conditions improve, critical levels of food insecurity remain in Gaza</title><link>https://www.foodsecurityportal.org/node/3762</link><description>Food security conditions in the Gaza Strip have improved since August when the IPC Famine Review Committee confirmed the existence of famine conditions. Despite this improvement, however, 1.6 million people—most of Gaza’s population—still face unacceptably high levels of acute food insecurity, according to the IPC’s latest alert.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>FAO Food Price Index Declines for Third Consecutive Month</title><link>https://www.foodsecurityportal.org/node/3760</link><description>The FAO Food Price Index fell for the third month in a row in November, declining by 1.2 percent. Prices declined for all commodities except cereals. The Index in November stood 2.1 percent below its year-earlier level and nearly 22 percent below the peak of March 2022.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>